# **GEORGE KURIA**

Telephone no: +254716284522 Email: gkungu962@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated IT Consultant and Customer Service Professional with over 5 years of experience offering customized solutions to increase sales and customer satisfaction. Developed expertise assessing client requirements, introducing optimal products, and building lasting client relationships. Logged detailed records for over 100 client interactions monthly. Seeking to apply relationship-building talents and technical knowledge in an IT consultant or remote role.

### **SKILLS**

Sales, Consultative Selling, IT Consulting, Information Systems, Desktop Support, Help Desk, Troubleshooting, Account Management, Product Consultation, Sales Reporting, Customer Relationship Management, Chinese Language Customer Service, Relationship Building, Interpersonal Skills, English Language Information Systems, Desktop Support, Help Desk, Troubleshooting

#### EXPERIENCE

## SALESPERSON | MARAMOS LIMITED | NAIROBI, KENYA | AUG. 2016 - SEP.2022

Roles and Achievements:

- Strengthened expertise in assessing client requirements for various products, enhancing individualized recommendations
- Exceeded monthly sales targets through dedicated client engagement and consultative needs analysis.
- Increased annual customer satisfaction scores by 31% by personally offering customized solutions and follow-up to boost loyalty.
- Situation: Needed to improve closing rates to hit individual sales goals. Task: Proactively engaged clients by listening to business and personal needs. Action: Persuasively presented optimal products and services through consultative approach. Result: Closed 15% more deals annually by building rapport.
- Built lasting client relationships through detailed customer profiles and follow-up, improving future lead generation.
- Logged comprehensive records of over 2,000 client interactions, expenses, and sales in company CRM, providing data to refine solutions.

# DATA ENTRY/ANALYSIS (PART-TIME) | AFRICA CLOUD SPACE | NAIROBI, KENYA | MAR. 2022 - 2023

Roles and Achievements:

- Streamlined data entry process, reducing completion time by 20%.
- Identified and corrected over 500 inaccurate records in the database.
- Collaborated with team to automate reporting, creating 5 new dynamic reports.
- Documented processes and trained 3 new hires on data entry guidelines.
- Liaised with department heads to understand changing data needs and maintain data integrity.
- Conducted audits ensuring excel sheets matched data in the database with 98% accuracy.

- Created macros and formulas in Excel leading to 70% faster data analysis.
- Identified duplicate records in the system and merged them to maintain data integrity.
- Provided analytical support for marketing campaigns, increasing lead conversion rate by 10%.
- Developed and implemented a new file classification system for improved version control.

# **EDUCATION**

United States International University Nairobi | **Bachelor of Science - Information Systems Technology** | 2022 - Present

Pan Africa Christian University | **Diploma in Communications** | 2016 - 2022

## REFEREES

Available Upon Request.